<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Suzanne Bellue</title>
    <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Suzanne Bellue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://silvia.rbind.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>WAVE Audit No. 1</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/blog/2021-a11y-website/01-wave-audit-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/blog/2021-a11y-website/01-wave-audit-1/</guid>
      <description>.page-main img { box-shadow: 0px 0px 2px 2px rgba( 0, 0, 0, 0.2 ); #/* ease | ease-in | ease-out | linear */ transition: transform ease-in-out 0.6s; } .page-main img:hover { transform: scale(1.4); }   Did you know that 97.4% of home pages have web accessibility failures??? 😱
 This finding is one of many from an accessibility analysis that non-profit WebAIM (Web Accessibility in Mind) conducts annually on home pages of the top one million websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Mobility with Subjective Beliefs: The Effects of Neighborhoods on Investment Choices</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/publication/smm-individual-neighborhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/publication/smm-individual-neighborhood/</guid>
      <description>Neighborhoods in the US shape future economics outcomes of children who grow up in them, and their endogenous demographic composition define who are the role models for those children. I develop and estimate a structural spatial equilibrium model of parental investments in which residential choices exogenously impact the human capital formation of children, and endogenously shape their expectations about the returns to educational investments. Under the assumption that agents are unable to perfectly estimate the bias that spatial sorting introduces, this model generates persistent misbeliefs about returns to educational investment that are correlated with earnings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessibility commitment</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/accessibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/accessibility/</guid>
      <description>Travel back to the home page, about page, or a11y series of blog posts.
Feedback     I welcome any feedback on the accessibility of my site and/or the educational materials I create. Please let me know if you encounter any accessibility barriers by using my contact form or mentioning me on Twitter @spcanelon and I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to respond promptly.
Thank you for visiting my site and for taking the time to read this page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LICENSE: CC-BY-SA</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Hugo Apéro: Converting a Blogdown Site from Hugo Academic</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/blog/hello-hugo-apero/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/blog/hello-hugo-apero/</guid>
      <description>A tutorial on how to take your personal Hugo Academic/Wowchemy website and convert it to the Hugo Apéro theme</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyTuesdayAltText</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/project/tidy-tuesday-alt-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/project/tidy-tuesday-alt-text/</guid>
      <description>About the data      The original data were collected and made available by Tom Mock ( @thomas_mock) using {rtweet}. These data are available in the TidyTuesday repository.
These tweets were processed and scraped for alternative text by Silvia Canelón ( @spcanelon)
 Data were filtered to remove tweets without attached media (e.g. images) Data were supplemented with reply tweets collected using {rtweet}. This was done to identify whether the original tweet or a reply tweet contained an external link (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying xaringan Slides: A Ten-Step GitHub Pages Workflow</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/blog/deploying-xaringan-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/blog/deploying-xaringan-slides/</guid>
      <description>A ten-step workflow for creating an HTML xaringan slide deck and deploying it to the web using GitHub Pages</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>useR!2021 Cost Conversion Tool</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/project/user-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/project/user-2021/</guid>
      <description>I created a cost conversion tool used for the useR!2021 Conference to adapt conference and sponsorship fees according to the country of residence. The cost conversion was done according to Gross Domestic Product (GDP) adjusted by Purchasing Power Parity (PPP) provided by the World Bank. We wanted conference attendees and sponsors from different parts of the world to be able to participate in useR! and believed that this is a fair approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enseñar Tecnología en Comunidad</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/project/teaching-tech-together-es/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/project/teaching-tech-together-es/</guid>
      <description>Enseñar Tecnología en Comunidad. Cómo crear lecciones que funcionen y construir una comunidad docente alrededor      Este proyecto llevó acabo la traducción al castellano del libro Teaching Tech Together escrito por Greg Wilson. El proyecto fue coordinado por mi amiga y colega Yanina Bellini Saibene.
Yo participé como traductora del capítulo &amp;ldquo;Motivation and Demotivation&amp;rdquo; y revisora del capítulo &amp;ldquo;Expertise and Memory.&amp;rdquo;
 Septiembre de 2020 – Diciembre de 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nhsr CSS Theme for xaringan</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/project/xaringan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/project/xaringan/</guid>
      <description>Theme      In preparation for a xaringan workshop I created for the NHS-R 2020 Conference, I designed a custom CSS theme with input from the NHS-R Community that followed the NHS identity guidelines. This theme was also contributed to the nhsrtheme package developed by Tom Jemmett.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing Your Work with xaringan</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/project/xaringan-nhs-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/project/xaringan-nhs-r/</guid>
      <description>Workshop description     This four-hour hands-on workshop is a gentle introduction to the xaringan package as a tool to create impressive presentation slides that can be deployed to the web for easy sharing.
Day 1 covers the nuts and bolts of creating presentation slides using xaringan and deploying them in HTML format for easy sharing with others.
Day 2 covers how to take your slides to the next level with the xaringanExtra package and how to customize slides with CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xaringan CSS Theme for nhsrtheme</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/project/nhsrtheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/project/nhsrtheme/</guid>
      <description>Theme      In preparation for a xaringan workshop I created for the NHS-R 2020 Conference, I designed a custom CSS theme with input from the NHS-R Community that followed the NHS identity guidelines. This theme was also contributed to the xaringan package developed by Yihui Xie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming certified as an RStudio Tidyverse Instructor</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/blog/rstudio-instructor-certification-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/blog/rstudio-instructor-certification-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>An overview of the RStudio Instructor certification process and collection of resources to support anyone on their certification journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing Hugo Academic&#39;s Dark Mode with Help from Atom</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/blog/dark-theme-custom-with-atom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/blog/dark-theme-custom-with-atom/</guid>
      <description>Tutorial on how to customize the dark mode in Hugo&amp;rsquo;s Academic theme with help from the Atom text editor package Pigments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from Trello to Airtable: Working with JSON Data in R</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/blog/trello-to-airtable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/blog/trello-to-airtable/</guid>
      <description>Tutorial on how to migrate your current Trello board to an Airtable base from start to finish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philly Center City Sips 2019: An Interactive Map</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/blog/ccd-sips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/blog/ccd-sips/</guid>
      <description>An interactive map showing restaurants participating in Philly’s Center City District Sips 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send me a note</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>https://silvia.rbind.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silvia.rbind.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>
 Teaching Assistant 2021: Demographic transition and development - STEG lecture - Pr. Michèle Tertilt 2017: Public Economics - Sciences Po Paris - Pr. Emeric Henry 2014: Macroeconomics - Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile - Pr. Matías Tapia     Research Assistant 2019 - .: Research assistant of Pr. Michèle Tertilt - Mannheim University 2015 - 2018: J-PAL Europe - Paris School of Economics 2015: J-PAL LAC - Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
