<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Suzanne Bellue</title>
    <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Suzanne Bellue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suzannebellue.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning and Mobile Phone Data Can Improve the Targeting of Humanitarian Assistance</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/targeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/targeting/</guid>
      <description>Targeting is a central challenge in the administration of anti-poverty programs: given available data, how does one rapidly identify the individuals and families with the greatest need? Here we show that non-traditional “big” data from satellites and mobile phone networks can improve the targeting of anti-poverty programs. Our analysis compares outcomes – including exclusion errors, total social welfare, and measures of fairness – under different targeting regimes. Relative to other feasible targeting options, the machine learning approach reduces errors of exclusion by 4-21%. These results highlight the potential for new data sources to contribute to humanitarian response efforts, particularly in crisis settings when traditional data are missing or out of date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LICENSE: CC-BY-SA</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Don&#39;t Poor Families Move? A Spatial Equilibrium of Pessimism and Overoptimism</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/smm-individual-neighborhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/smm-individual-neighborhood/</guid>
      <description>Children’s neighborhoods in the United States matter for their economic outcomes as adults, and yet, low-income families tend to live in low-opportunity areas. While empirically affordability and moving costs do not fully explain this pattern, I argue that local information transmission about returns to parental investment can explain it. I develop and estimate a spatial equilibrium model of an average commuting zone with multiple neighborhoods, altruistic families and imperfect information about returns to parental investment. In this model, exogenous neighborhood quality affects children’s human capital, while endogenous neighborhood demographics shape their beliefs about the returns to parental investment. Under the assumption that agents suffer from a selection neglect that spatial sorting introduces, this model generates persistent misbeliefs that are correlated with earnings. The estimated model captures empirical patterns regarding the correlation between subjective beliefs and earnings, intergenerational mobility and residential choices. Place based policies that decrease neighborhood quality heterogeneity within a commuting zone can substantially improve intergenerational mobility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macroeconomic Consequences of Early Education Tracking</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/tracking/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Training Program, Teacher Practices and Student Performance in Science: Evidence from a Randomized Study in French Primary Schools</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/teacher-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/teacher-training/</guid>
      <description>We conduct a large randomized study to assess the impact of an in-service teacher training program on inquiry-based teaching in sciences. The randomized study is conducted in several French primary schools, comprises randomly assigned 134 teachers and two cohorts of about 2500 students. In addition to standardized student test score, we collect information on teacher quantitative and qualitative practices and pedagogical knowledge. We find that the training program (80 hours over 2 years) significantly increase the weekly hours of science as well as the number of hands-on science experiments conducted in class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employment Transitions: Mechanisms For Gender Earnings Gap</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/smm-gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/smm-gender/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/googlecd821d012a564e1e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/googlecd821d012a564e1e/</guid>
      <description>google-site-verification: googlecd821d012a564e1e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
