<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Suzanne Bellue</title>
    <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Suzanne Bellue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suzannebellue.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Solow Growth Model</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/quiz/solow_sim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/quiz/solow_sim/</guid>
      <description> \[ y_t = k_t^α \] \[ k_{t+1}-k_{t} = s k_t^\alpha - (n + δ)k_t \] Savings rate (s): Population growth (n): Depreciation (δ): Capital share (α): Initial capital (k₀): </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Residential and Social Mobility: A Quantitative Analysis of Parental Decisions with Social Learning</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>In the U.S., beliefs about parenting and parental choices differ across socioeconomic groups. This paper develops an overlapping generations model with social learning, where young adults form beliefs about parenting by observing neighbors but may make inference mistakes due to selection neglect&amp;mdash;imperfect correction for selection. In equilibrium, residential segregation generates information frictions that foster heterogeneous beliefs and distort parenting decisions. When calibrated to the U.S., the model suggests these beliefs reduce equity and efficiency, and housing vouchers can enhance both social mobility and aggregate income. In contrast, a model that replaces beliefs with fixed preference heterogeneity predicts income losses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Le modèle de Solow</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/quiz/solow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/quiz/solow/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficiency and Equity of Education Tracking: A Quantitative Analysis</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/tracking/</guid>
      <description>We study the long-run macroeconomic, distributional, and intergenerational effects of school tracking&amp;mdash;the allocation of students to different types of schools&amp;mdash;by incorporating school track decisions into a general-equilibrium heterogeneous-agent overlapping-generations model. The key ingredient in the model is the child skill production technology, where a child’s skill development depends on her peers and the instruction pace in her school track. We show analytically that this technology can rationalize reduced-form evidence on the effects of school tracking on the distribution of child skills. We then calibrate the model using representative data from Germany, a country with a very early school tracking policy. Our calibrated model predicts that an education reform that postpones the tracking age from ten to fourteen generates sizable improvements in intergenerational mobility but comes at the cost of modest losses in aggregate human capital and economic output, reducing aggregate welfare. This efficiency-mobility trade-off is rooted in the effects of longer comprehensive schooling on child learning and depends crucially on the presence of general equilibrium effects in the labor market. Finally, our calibrated model predicts that policies reducing the parental influence in the school track choice increase both social mobility and aggregate economic output, improving aggregate welfare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Information in the Family</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/family_asymmetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/family_asymmetry/</guid>
      <description>We theoretically and empirically investigate the hypothesis that private information plays a role within families. While standard theory implies that changes in relative income do not affect relative consumption in couples, we find a positive relationship in Dutch panel data. We collected data on how spouses share information with each other within the same panel and split our sample into those couples that are fully informed about each other&amp;rsquo;s income and those that are not. We find that the positive relationship between income and consumption shares is entirely driven by those couples that are not fully informed about each other&amp;rsquo;s income. This holds true when adding couple fixed effects, so that, indeed, a change in relative income within a given couple affects their consumption sharing. These findings are consistent with an optimal contracting model with private information. In the model, to provide incentives to share information with each other, the spouse who receives an income increase gets a larger promised utility, which is isomorphic to an increase in the bargaining weight. These findings suggest that information asymmetries are more relevant for families than previously believed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating Impact with Surveys versus Digital Traces: Evidence from Randomized Cash Transfers in Togo</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/togoimpact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/togoimpact/</guid>
      <description>We study whether program impacts can be estimated using a combination of digital trace data and machine learning. In a randomized controlled trial of cash transfers in Togo, endline survey data indicate positive treatment effects on food security, mental health, and perceived economic status. However, estimates of impact based solely on predicted endline outcomes (generated using trace data and machine learning, which do successfully predict baseline poverty) are generally not statistically significant. When post-treatment outcome data are used in conjunction with predictions to estimate treatment effects, predicted impacts are similar to those estimated using surveys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Effective Teacher Training Falls Short in the Classroom: Evidence from an Experiment in Primary Schools</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/teacher-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/teacher-training/</guid>
      <description>Although in-service teacher training programs are designed to enhance the performance of several cohorts of students, there is little evidence on the persistence of their effects. We present the two-year results of a randomized study of an intensive in-service teacher training program conducted in France during and after the training program&amp;rsquo;s implementation. Our results highlight the short-run effectiveness of the training program: it successfully improves students&amp;rsquo; performance but only during the implementation year. A detailed analysis of teachers&amp;rsquo; outcomes indicates that teachers changed their pedagogical vision and practices but afterward struggled to apply skills to contents not directly covered during training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employment Transitions: Mechanisms for Gender Earnings Gap </title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/gender/</guid>
      <description>We use German administrative data to compare women&amp;rsquo;s and men&amp;rsquo;s career choices and labor income profiles over their working lives. We find a significant and robust gender gap in job-to-job transitions. When working full-time, women are less likely than men to transition from one employer to another. The first finding is that while commuting preferences and sector selection do not explain this gap, the birth event largely explains it. Second, we want to quantify the consequences of the gender gap in job-to-job transitions for the gender earnings gap. If full-time job-to-job transitions increase wage growth, this phenomenon most likely contributes to the well-documented child penalty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning and Mobile Phone Data Can Improve the Targeting of Humanitarian Assistance</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/targeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/targeting/</guid>
      <description>Targeting is a central challenge in the administration of anti-poverty programs: given available data, how does one rapidly identify the individuals and families with the greatest need? Here we show that non-traditional “big” data from satellites and mobile phone networks can improve the targeting of anti-poverty programs. Our analysis compares outcomes – including exclusion errors, total social welfare, and measures of fairness – under different targeting regimes. Relative to other feasible targeting options, the machine learning approach reduces errors of exclusion by 4-21%. These results highlight the potential for new data sources to contribute to humanitarian response efforts, particularly in crisis settings when traditional data are missing or out of date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LICENSE: CC-BY-SA</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/googlecd821d012a564e1e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/googlecd821d012a564e1e/</guid>
      <description>google-site-verification: googlecd821d012a564e1e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/2022-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/2022-reading/</guid>
      <description>%%&amp;mdash; title: &amp;ldquo;Impacts of a Multi-component Reading Intervention for 6th-grade Students: Results from a Clustered Randomized Controlled Trial&amp;rdquo; author: &amp;ldquo; Marina Tual, Maryse Bianco, Pascal Bressoux and Marc Gurgand&amp;rdquo; date: &amp;lsquo;2020-10-24&amp;rsquo; slug: reading tags:
Work in progress summary: &amp;ldquo;This study aimed to design, implement and analyze the effectiveness of a multicomponent reading comprehension intervention for sixth-grade students with reading difficulties. We conducted a clustered randomized study with 21 French middle schools.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
