<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Suzanne Bellue</title>
    <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Suzanne Bellue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suzannebellue.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning and Mobile Phone Data Can Improve the Targeting of Humanitarian Assistance</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/targeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/targeting/</guid>
      <description>Targeting is a central challenge in the administration of anti-poverty programs: given available data, how does one rapidly identify the individuals and families with the greatest need? Here we show that non-traditional “big” data from satellites and mobile phone networks can improve the targeting of anti-poverty programs. Our analysis compares outcomes – including exclusion errors, total social welfare, and measures of fairness – under different targeting regimes. Relative to other feasible targeting options, the machine learning approach reduces errors of exclusion by 4-21%. These results highlight the potential for new data sources to contribute to humanitarian response efforts, particularly in crisis settings when traditional data are missing or out of date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LICENSE: CC-BY-SA</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Don&#39;t Poor Families Move? A Spatial Equilibrium of Parental Investment with Imperfect Information</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>By choosing neighborhoods in which to live, parents affect future economic outcomes of their children. Nevertheless, low-income families who benefit from housing vouchers tend to remain in low-opportunity areas. While empirical evidence suggests that affordability and moving costs do not fully explain this pattern, in this paper I will argue that this phenomenon can results from local information transmission about returns on parental investment. After presenting empirical evidence of local transmission of information, I develop and calibrate a spatial equilibrium model of an average commuting zone with multiple neighborhoods, families and imperfect information about returns on parental investment. In this model, adults&#39; human capital is determined by two parental investment choices (neighborhood and time) and by one exogenous luck shock. During childhood, agents learn about returns on parental investment using information at the local level. Under the assumption that children do not know the local distribution of the luck shock, this model displays persistent delusion that is correlated with earnings. The calibrated model captures empirical patterns regarding the correlation between parental investment and education, intergenerational mobility and residential choices. Place based policies that decrease neighborhood quality heterogeneity and segregation within a commuting zone substantially improve intergenerational mobility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macroeconomic Consequences of Early Education Tracking</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/tracking/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Training Program, Teacher Practices and Student Performance in Science: Evidence from a Randomized Study in French Primary Schools</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/teacher-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/teacher-training/</guid>
      <description>We conduct a randomized study to assess the impact of an in-service teacher training program on inquiry-based learning in science in French primary schools. The study comprises 134 randomly assigned volunteer teachers and two cohorts of about 2,500 students. In addition to student test scores, we collect information on teacher practices and pedagogical knowledge. We find that the training program (80 hours over two years) increases the weekly hours of science instruction as well as the number of science experiments conducted in class. Yet, one year later, most of these effects disappear. Consistently, while we find small effects on students’ scientific knowledge during the last year of the training program, these effects are also short-lived. These results highlight the difficulty to train experienced teachers in a way that has deep and long-lasting influence on their practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employment Transitions: Mechanisms For Gender Earnings Gap</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/smm-gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/smm-gender/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/googlecd821d012a564e1e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/googlecd821d012a564e1e/</guid>
      <description>google-site-verification: googlecd821d012a564e1e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
