<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work in progress on Suzanne Bellue</title>
    <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work in progress on Suzanne Bellue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning and Mobile Phone Data Can Improve the Targeting of Humanitarian Assistance</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/targeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/targeting/</guid>
      <description>Targeting is a central challenge in the administration of anti-poverty programs: given available data, how does one rapidly identify the individuals and families with the greatest need? Here we show that non-traditional “big” data from satellites and mobile phone networks can improve the targeting of anti-poverty programs. Our analysis compares outcomes – including exclusion errors, total social welfare, and measures of fairness – under different targeting regimes. Relative to other feasible targeting options, the machine learning approach reduces errors of exclusion by 4-21%. These results highlight the potential for new data sources to contribute to humanitarian response efforts, particularly in crisis settings when traditional data are missing or out of date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Don&#39;t Poor Families Move? A Spatial Equilibrium of Parental Decisions with Imperfect Information</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>Parents&#39; neighborhood choices shape children’s economic opportunities in the United States. However, most children raised in bottom-quality neighborhoods still live in low-quality neighborhoods in adulthood. Could parents&#39; neighborhood choices also affect their children&amp;rsquo;s future choices? I develop a quantitative spatial model of parental decisions that incorporates a novel mechanism: social learning about the technology of skill formation. Segregation generates information frictions that systematically distort parents&#39; subjective beliefs and behavior. Using several United States representative datasets, I calibrate the model to the average commuting zone in the country. The calibrated model matches targeted and non-targeted parental behaviors and generates an endogenous distribution of subjective beliefs. I find that a relatively modest level of delusion increases inequality by 3% and decreases social mobility by 12%. Housing vouchers improve the neighborhood quality of eligible families, raising children&amp;rsquo;s future earnings. When scaled-up, general equilibrium responses in local prices and subjective beliefs amplify the policy effects on eligible households, reducing inequality and improving social mobility. Ignoring subjective belief responses greatly undermines the policy effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macroeconomic Consequences of Early Education Tracking</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/tracking/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Training Program, Teacher Practices and Student Performance in Science: Evidence from a Randomized Study in French Primary Schools</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/teacher-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/teacher-training/</guid>
      <description>We conduct a randomized study to assess the impact of an in-service teacher training program on inquiry-based learning in science in French primary schools. The study comprises 134 randomly assigned volunteer teachers and two cohorts of about 2,500 students. In addition to student test scores, we collect information on teacher practices and pedagogical knowledge. We find that the training program (80 hours over two years) increases the weekly hours of science instruction as well as the number of science experiments conducted in class. Yet, one year later, most of these effects disappear. Consistently, while we find small effects on students’ scientific knowledge during the last year of the training program, these effects are also short-lived. These results highlight the difficulty to train experienced teachers in a way that has deep and long-lasting influence on their practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employment Transitions: Mechanisms For Gender Earnings Gap </title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/smm-gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/smm-gender/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
