<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work in progress on Suzanne Bellue</title>
    <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work in progress on Suzanne Bellue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Employment Transitions: Mechanisms For Gender Earnings Gap </title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/gender/</guid>
      <description>We use German administrative data to compare women&amp;rsquo;s and men&amp;rsquo;s career choices and labor income profiles over their working lives. We find a significant and robust gender gap in job-to-job transitions. When working full-time, women are less likely than men to transition from one employer to another. The first finding is that while commuting preferences and sector selection do not explain this gap, the birth event largely explains it. Second, we want to quantify the consequences of the gender gap in job-to-job transitions for the gender earnings gap. If full-time job-to-job transitions increase wage growth, this phenomenon most likely contributes to the well-documented child penalty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macroeconomic Consequences of Early Education Tracking</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/tracking/</guid>
      <description>This paper assesses the consequences of early school tracking on intergenerational social mobility and inequalities in Germany. We develop a quantitative, overlapping-generation life-cycle model in which we incorporate two critical elements of the debate around tracking in school: (i) homogeneous peer groups enhance learning (ii) however, there is uncertainty about the skills of young children and a strong influence of the socio-economic situation of the parents in the tracking decision. We quantify each channel by calibrating the model to match NEPS test score data&amp;mdash;a representative panel of German pupils. We then use the calibrated model to assess the consequences of postponing school tracking on social mobility, inequality, and efficiency. &lt;em&gt;Slides for this project are available upon request.&lt;/em&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Cash Transfers in Togo: Digital Data Do Not Recover Treatment Effects Found in Survey Data</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/togoimpact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/togoimpact/</guid>
      <description>Digital cash transfer programs were setup rapidly during the COVID-19 pandemic and are increasingly common post-pandemic. In a randomized evaluation, we find that Togo&amp;rsquo;s Novissi program, which identified beneficiaries using poverty proxied by mobile phone data and provided US$13-15 in monthly mobile cash transfers, yielded modestly positive, statistically significant treatment effects on self-reported food security, financial health, and mental health. However, mobile phone data records, previously successful at predicting poverty levels, do not generate similar treatment effects to the survey data. Our results have key implications for using mobile phone data as a proxy for vulnerability in policy impact measurement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Don&#39;t Poor Families Move? A Spatial Equilibrium Analysis of Parental Decisions with Social Learning</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>In the United States, childhood neighborhood quality shapes adulthood economic opportunities. However, most children raised in bottom-quality neighborhoods still live in low-quality neighborhoods in adulthood. Could childhood neighborhood directly affect adulthood choices? I develop a quantitative spatial model of parental decisions that incorporates a novel mechanism: social learning about the technology of skill formation. Segregation generates information frictions that systematically distort parents&#39; subjective beliefs and behavior. I calibrate the model using several United States representative datasets. The calibrated model matches targeted and non-targeted parental behavior and generates an endogenous distribution of subjective beliefs. I find a relatively modest level of delusion that increases the income Gini index by 3% and the intergenerational rank-rank slope by 12%. A housing voucher policy improves the neighborhood quality of eligible families, raising children&amp;rsquo;s future earnings. When scaling up the policy, long-run and general equilibrium responses in subjective beliefs amplify the policy effects. Inequality reduces, and intergenerational mobility improves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning and Mobile Phone Data Can Improve the Targeting of Humanitarian Assistance</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/targeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/targeting/</guid>
      <description>Targeting is a central challenge in the administration of anti-poverty programs: given available data, how does one rapidly identify the individuals and families with the greatest need? Here we show that non-traditional “big” data from satellites and mobile phone networks can improve the targeting of anti-poverty programs. Our analysis compares outcomes – including exclusion errors, total social welfare, and measures of fairness – under different targeting regimes. Relative to other feasible targeting options, the machine learning approach reduces errors of exclusion by 4-21%. These results highlight the potential for new data sources to contribute to humanitarian response efforts, particularly in crisis settings when traditional data are missing or out of date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Effective Teacher Training Falls Short in the Classroom: Evidence from an Experiment in Primary Schools</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/teacher-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/teacher-training/</guid>
      <description>Although in-service teacher training programs are designed to enhance the performance of several cohorts of students, there is little evidence on the persistence of their effects. We present the two-year results of a large-scale randomized study of an intensive in-service teacher training program conducted in France during and after the training program&amp;rsquo;s implementation year. Our results highlight the short-run effectiveness of the training program: it successfully improves students&#39; performance but only during the implementation year. A detailed analysis of teachers&#39; outcomes indicates that teachers changed their pedagogical vision and practices but struggled to apply skills to contents not directly covered during training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impacts of a Multi-component Reading Intervention for 6th-grade Students: Results from a Clustered Randomized Controlled Trial</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/reading/</guid>
      <description>This study aimed to design, implement and analyze the effectiveness of a multicomponent reading comprehension intervention for sixth-grade students with reading difficulties. We conducted a clustered randomized study with 21 French middle schools. In ten of them, teachers have implemented fluency workshops and explicit comprehension instruction. We measure the impact on 568 target students, and show no statistically significant effect of the intervention. The lack of statistical effects contrasts with observations indicating that, overall, the school leaders and the teachers declared to be satisfied with the proposed device and the actions conducted. However, our results align with a growing research base showing that setting up additional support and disseminating research tools is not enough to observe real progress in students’ performance. Indeed, our field observations revealed significant implementation difficulties.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
