<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work in progress on Suzanne Bellue</title>
    <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/tags/work-in-progress/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work in progress on Suzanne Bellue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suzannebellue.github.io/tags/work-in-progress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Private Information in the Family</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/family_asymmetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/family_asymmetry/</guid>
      <description>We theoretically and empirically investigate the hypothesis that private information plays a role within families. While standard theory implies that changes in relative income do not affect relative consumption in couples, we find a positive relationship in Dutch panel data. We collected data on how spouses share information with each other within the same panel and split our sample into those couples that are fully informed about each other&amp;rsquo;s income and those that are not. We find that the positive relationship between income and consumption shares is entirely driven by those couples that are not fully informed about each other&amp;rsquo;s income. This holds true when adding couple fixed effects, so that, indeed, a change in relative income within a given couple affects their consumption sharing. These findings are consistent with an optimal contracting model with private information. In the model, to provide incentives to share information with each other, the spouse who receives an income increase gets a larger promised utility, which is isomorphic to an increase in the bargaining weight. These findings suggest that information asymmetries are more relevant for families than previously believed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employment Transitions: Mechanisms For Gender Earnings Gap </title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/gender/</guid>
      <description>We use German administrative data to compare women&amp;rsquo;s and men&amp;rsquo;s career choices and labor income profiles over their working lives. We find a significant and robust gender gap in job-to-job transitions. When working full-time, women are less likely than men to transition from one employer to another. The first finding is that while commuting preferences and sector selection do not explain this gap, the birth event largely explains it. Second, we want to quantify the consequences of the gender gap in job-to-job transitions for the gender earnings gap. If full-time job-to-job transitions increase wage growth, this phenomenon most likely contributes to the well-documented child penalty.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
