<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work in progress on Suzanne Bellue</title>
    <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/tags/work-in-progress/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work in progress on Suzanne Bellue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suzannebellue.github.io/tags/work-in-progress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Don&#39;t Poor Families Move? A Spatial Equilibrium of Pessimism and Overoptimism</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/smm-individual-neighborhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/smm-individual-neighborhood/</guid>
      <description>Children’s neighborhoods in the United States matter for their economic outcomes as adults, and yet, low-income families tend to live in low-opportunity areas. While empirically affordability and moving costs do not fully explain this pattern, I argue that local information transmission about returns to parental investment can explain this pattern. I develop and estimate a spatial equilibrium model of an average commuting zone with multiple neighborhoods, altruistic families and imperfect information about returns to parental investment. In this model, exogenous neighborhood quality affects children’s human capital, while endogenous neighborhood demographics shape their beliefs about the returns to parental investment. Under the assumption that agents suffer from a selection neglect that spatial sorting introduces, this model generates persistent misbeliefs that are correlated with earnings. The estimated model captures empirical patterns regarding the correlation between subjective beliefs and earnings, intergenerational mobility and residential choices. Place based policies that decrease neighborhood quality heterogeneity within a commuting zone can substantially improve intergenerational mobility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macroeconomic Consequences of Early Education Tracking</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/tracking/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employment Transitions: Mechanisms For Gender Earnings Gap</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/smm-gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/smm-gender/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
