<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work in progress on Suzanne Bellue</title>
    <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/tags/work-in-progress/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work in progress on Suzanne Bellue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suzannebellue.github.io/tags/work-in-progress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Employment Transitions: Mechanisms For Gender Earnings Gap </title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/gender/</guid>
      <description>We use German administrative data to compare women&amp;rsquo;s and men&amp;rsquo;s career choices and labor income profiles over their working lives. We find a significant and robust gender gap in job-to-job transitions. When working full-time, women are less likely than men to transition from one employer to another. The first finding is that while commuting preferences and sector selection do not explain this gap, the birth event largely explains it. Second, we want to quantify the consequences of the gender gap in job-to-job transitions for the gender earnings gap. If full-time job-to-job transitions increase wage growth, this phenomenon most likely contributes to the well-documented child penalty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macroeconomic Consequences of Early Education Tracking</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/tracking/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Cash Transfers in Togo: Digital Data Do Not Recover Treatment Effects Found in Survey Data</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/togoimpact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/togoimpact/</guid>
      <description>Digital cash transfer programs were setup rapidly during the COVID-19 pandemic and are increasingly common post-pandemic. In a randomized evaluation, we find that Togo&amp;rsquo;s Novissi program, which identified beneficiaries using poverty proxied by mobile phone data and provided US$13-15 in monthly mobile cash transfers, yielded modestly positive, statistically significant treatment effects on self-reported food security, financial health, and mental health. However, mobile phone data records, previously successful at predicting poverty levels, do not generate similar treatment effects to the survey data. Our results have key implications for using mobile phone data as a proxy for vulnerability in policy impact measurement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
