<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Working Papers and Publications on Suzanne Bellue</title>
    <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/tags/working-papers-and-publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Working Papers and Publications on Suzanne Bellue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suzannebellue.github.io/tags/working-papers-and-publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning and Mobile Phone Data Can Improve the Targeting of Humanitarian Assistance</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/targeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/targeting/</guid>
      <description>Targeting is a central challenge in the administration of anti-poverty programs: given available data, how does one rapidly identify the individuals and families with the greatest need? Here we show that non-traditional “big” data from satellites and mobile phone networks can improve the targeting of anti-poverty programs. Our analysis compares outcomes – including exclusion errors, total social welfare, and measures of fairness – under different targeting regimes. Relative to other feasible targeting options, the machine learning approach reduces errors of exclusion by 4-21%. These results highlight the potential for new data sources to contribute to humanitarian response efforts, particularly in crisis settings when traditional data are missing or out of date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Training Program, Teacher Practices and Student Performance in Science: Evidence from a Randomized Study in French Primary Schools</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/teacher-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/teacher-training/</guid>
      <description>Although in-service teacher training programs are designed to enhance the performance of several cohorts of students, there is little evidence on the persistence of their effects. We present the two-year results of a large-scale randomized study of an intensive in-service teacher training program conducted in France during and after the training program&amp;rsquo;s implementation year. Our results highlight the short-run effectiveness of the training program: it successfully improves students&#39; performance but only during the implementation year. A detailed analysis of teachers&#39; outcomes indicates that teachers changed their pedagogical vision and practices but struggled to apply skills to contents not directly covered during training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impacts of a Multi-component Reading Intervention for 6th-grade Students: Results from a Clustered Randomized Controlled Trial</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/reading/</guid>
      <description>This study aimed to design, implement and analyze the effectiveness of a multicomponent reading comprehension intervention for sixth-grade students with reading difficulties. We conducted a clustered randomized study with 21 French middle schools. In ten of them, teachers have implemented fluency workshops and explicit comprehension instruction. We measure the impact on 568 target students, and show no statistically significant effect of the intervention. The lack of statistical effects contrasts with observations indicating that, overall, the school leaders and the teachers declared to be satisfied with the proposed device and the actions conducted. However, our results align with a growing research base showing that setting up additional support and disseminating research tools is not enough to observe real progress in students’ performance. Indeed, our field observations revealed significant implementation difficulties.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
