<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Job Market Paper on Suzanne Bellue</title>
    <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/tags/job-market-paper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Job Market Paper on Suzanne Bellue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suzannebellue.github.io/tags/job-market-paper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Don&#39;t Poor Families Move? A Spatial Equilibrium Analysis of Parental Decisions with Social Learning</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/research/neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>In the United States, childhood neighborhood quality shapes adulthood economic opportunities. However, most children raised in bottom-quality neighborhoods still live in low-quality neighborhoods in adulthood. Could childhood neighborhood directly affect adulthood choices? I develop a quantitative spatial model of parental decisions that incorporates a novel mechanism: social learning about the technology of skill formation. Segregation generates information frictions that systematically distort parents&#39; subjective beliefs and behaviors. I calibrate the model using several United States representative datasets. The calibrated model matches targeted and non-targeted parental behaviors and generates an endogenous distribution of subjective beliefs. I find a relatively modest level of delusion that increases inequality by 3% and decreases intergenerational mobility by  12%. A housing voucher policy improves the neighborhood quality of eligible families, raising children&amp;rsquo;s future earnings. When scaling up the policy, long-run and general equilibrium responses in subjective beliefs amplify the policy effects. Inequality reduces, and intergenerational mobility improves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
