<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work in progress on Suzanne Bellue</title>
    <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work in progress on Suzanne Bellue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suzannebellue.github.io/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Social Mobility with Subjective Beliefs: The Effects of Neighborhoods on Investment Choices</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/publication/smm-individual-neighborhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/publication/smm-individual-neighborhood/</guid>
      <description>Neighborhoods in the US shape future economics outcomes of children who grow up in them, and their endogenous demographic composition define who are the role models for those children. I develop and estimate a structural spatial equilibrium model of parental investments in which residential choices exogenously impact the human capital formation of children, and endogenously shape their expectations about the returns to educational investments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macroeconomic Consequences of Early Education Tracking</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/publication/tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/publication/tracking/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Training Program, Teacher Practices and Student Performance in Science: Evidence from a Randomized Study in French Primary Schools</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/publication/teacher-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/publication/teacher-training/</guid>
      <description>We conduct a large randomized study to assess the impact of an in-service teacher training program on inquiry-based teaching in sciences. The randomized study is conducted in several French primary schools, comprises randomly assigned 134 teachers and two cohorts of about 2500 students. In addition to standardized student test score, we collect information on teacher quantitative and qualitative practices and pedagogical knowledge. We find that the training program (80 hours over 2 years) significantly increase the weekly hours of science as well as the number of hands-on science experiments conducted in class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employment Transitions: Mechanisms For Gender Earnings Gap</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/publication/smm-gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/publication/smm-gender/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
