<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>xaringan on Suzanne Bellue</title>
    <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/tags/xaringan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in xaringan on Suzanne Bellue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suzannebellue.github.io/tags/xaringan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deploying xaringan Slides: A Ten-Step GitHub Pages Workflow</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/blog/deploying-xaringan-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/blog/deploying-xaringan-slides/</guid>
      <description>A ten-step workflow for creating an HTML xaringan slide deck and deploying it to the web using GitHub Pages</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nhsr CSS Theme for xaringan</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/project/xaringan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/project/xaringan/</guid>
      <description>Theme      In preparation for a xaringan workshop I created for the NHS-R 2020 Conference, I designed a custom CSS theme with input from the NHS-R Community that followed the NHS identity guidelines. This theme was also contributed to the nhsrtheme package developed by Tom Jemmett.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing Your Work with xaringan</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/project/xaringan-nhs-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/project/xaringan-nhs-r/</guid>
      <description>Workshop description     This four-hour hands-on workshop is a gentle introduction to the xaringan package as a tool to create impressive presentation slides that can be deployed to the web for easy sharing.
Day 1 covers the nuts and bolts of creating presentation slides using xaringan and deploying them in HTML format for easy sharing with others.
Day 2 covers how to take your slides to the next level with the xaringanExtra package and how to customize slides with CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xaringan CSS Theme for nhsrtheme</title>
      <link>https://suzannebellue.github.io/project/nhsrtheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannebellue.github.io/project/nhsrtheme/</guid>
      <description>Theme      In preparation for a xaringan workshop I created for the NHS-R 2020 Conference, I designed a custom CSS theme with input from the NHS-R Community that followed the NHS identity guidelines. This theme was also contributed to the xaringan package developed by Yihui Xie.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
